Amir Hakim Bin Amir Sharifuddin

Bandar Baru Bangi, +60 13-3503837, amirh1012@gmail.com



PROFILE

Experienced in website management and development, I've shaped engaging online experiences for major platforms like Petrosains and Petronas Twin Towers. Adept at driving projects from concept to success. Let's bring innovation to your team together!

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Jun 2023 — Present

GEES - Web Development & Management, Petrosains/Petronas

Kuala Lumpur

- Updated daily content on the Petrosains and Petronas Twin Towers websites.
- Conducted user acceptance testing (UAT) and provided reports for the deployment of the new Petrosains website.
- Conducted extensive database cleanup for Petrosains member records, ensuring data accuracy and integrity for streamlined operations.
- Drove website management for Petrosains and Petronas Twin Towers online stores, overseeing SKU visuals and updates.
- Developed a mock starbucks website for upskilling on new cms platform.
- Skills: Wordpress, Elementor, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Excel

Aug 2021 — Oct 2021

Internship, TM Sdn. Bhd.

Kuala Lumpur

- Assisted in developing an AI machine to assist Telekom's Customer services.
- Exposed to machine learning model development.
- Assisted the engineer to perform the company digitization.
- Skills: Python, Jupyter, Excel

EDUCATION

Sep 2018 — Mar 2023

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, UPM

Serdang

Related courses:

Web (HTML), Database (SQL), Imaging Process, Robotic, Embedded Systems, Operating System, Microprocessor, Engineering Project Management.

Extracurricular Activities:

- College Representative Council of UPM Tenth College 2019/2020.
 - Facilitated the Executive of Discipline to provide best leadership experiences for participants. I
- College representative in badmiton.
 - Represent as UPM Tenth College badminton athlete to play until semi-final.
- President of Kolej Sepuluh technical team.
 - Led 50 committee members and experienced in providing technical support for all events under Tenth College, UPM.

SKILLS	HTML	Wordpress
	CSS/Bootstrap	MySQL
	JavaScript	РНР
	React.js	C++

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Weather App

- Developed a responsive Weather App utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Integrated OpenWeatherMap's API to dynamically fetch and display real-time weather data for specified cities.
- Retrieval and presentation of key weather parameters such as temperature, weather conditions, humidity, and wind speed.

Starbucks Website Redesign

- bak.amerakim.name.my.
- Redesigned the Starbucks website proficiently using WordPress and Elementor, refining skills in website development and design.
- Applied customization techniques within WordPress and Elementor to tailor the Starbucks website, demonstrating adaptability and skill in adapting these platforms to meet specific design needs.
- Proficient in harnessing the capabilities of WordPress to effectively manage and optimize a wide array of post types and listings. Skilled in creating, organizing, and refining content across diverse formats within the WordPress ecosystem.
- Demonstrated expertise in maximizing visibility and engagement by strategically managing and enhancing post types and listings to achieve superior content performance.

Web & Database Project (Online Library Booking System)

- Designed a website for students and lecturers to borrow books through online method.
- Linked the website with database for monitoring and accounts storing.

FPGA Based Color Recognition System

 Final Year Project, developed a feasible algorithm that could detect primary colors by comparing the number of pixels captured from the camera using FPGA.

Embedded Systems Project (Smart Robot for Urban Farming)

 Designed an IoT system for monitoring purpose and instruct user in terms of planting / harvesting.

CERTIFICATIONS

2024 Full-Stack Web Development

Full course on fullstack web development by Nexpert Academy.

Course Includes HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js, Node.js and PHP.

22 Innovate Malaysia 2022

Participated in nationwide competition to design an FPGA color recognition system using Verilog according to industry standard.

LANGUAGES English Highly proficient Malay Native speaker

DR. FAISUL ARIF BIN AHMAD @ MOHD YUSOFF from Universiti Putra Malaysia

faisul@upm.edu.my · 03-9769 4318

Abdul Rahman bin Ab Karim from Petrosains

abdrahman.abkarim@petronas.com.my · 017-6548645

NOOR ISMALIZA ISMAIL from PETROSAINS

ismaliza.ismail@petronas.com.my · 03-2331 1814

2022

REFERENCES